MAN:
Sandra – I seem to remember you had some family visitors staying with you recently.
SANDRA:
Yeah that’s right.
My brother and his family were here a couple of months ago.
MAN:
OK good.
Well I wanted to ask your advice – I’ve got my cousin
and her family visiting next month and as I don’t have kids I’ve no
idea where to take them.
SANDRA:
Right.
What about accommodation?
Are they going to stay with you in your flat?
MAN:
No, thankfully – there wouldn’t be room – my cousin wants me to recommend
a hotel.
Do you know anywhere?
SANDRA:
Yes, I do actually.
I always recommend people stay at the Kings Hotel.
MAN:
Where’s that near?
SANDRA:
It’s about five minutes’ walk from Murray Station – so nice and central.
It’s actually on George Street.
MAN:
Oh yes I know.
I think they’re on quite a tight budget – so how much roughly is
it to stay there?
SANDRA:
If you book a family room it’s about £125 per night.
My brother paid for two double rooms in the end
and I think that was around £95 for each room.
MAN:
Oh that’s not too bad.
SANDRA:
So how old are your cousin’s kids?
MAN:
Twelve and nine.
So I want to organise some trips while they’re here.
MAN:
I was thinking of doing a bus tour of the city centre – as
none of them have been here before.
SANDRA:
Those bus tours are quite expensive.
I think it’s better to do a walking tour – it gives you a
much better feel for the city.
SANDRA:
There’s one that starts from Carlton Square.
It takes a couple of hours and doesn’t cost that much.
MAN:
Sounds good.
I’ll look that up – thanks.
SANDRA:
If the weather’s nice, one thing you could do is visit the old
fort.
You can get there by boat.
The whole trip takes half a day.
MAN:
That’s a really good idea.
I’d like to do that myself.
MAN:
And if the weather’s bad I was thinking they could go to the Science
Museum.
But maybe they could do that when I’m at work.
SANDRA:
Yeah – don’t forget it’s closed on Mondays.
MAN:
They’re here from Saturday for four nights – so Tuesday would be best, I
think.
SANDRA:
Mmm,
and it won’t be so crowded then.
Saturdays are terrible.
SANDRA:
I took my kids to the exhibition on old computers there
and it was far too crowded.
I wanted to go back but it’s finished now.
MAN:
That’s a shame.
My cousin’s kids would have enjoyed that.
SANDRA:
There’s another one starting soon on space which looks really good too.
MAN:
OK, well I’ll mention that to my cousin.
SANDRA:
Have you thought about where to take them to eat?
MAN:
Well I really like all the food stalls at Clacton Market.
My cousin’s vegetarian – I know it’s one of the best places for that
kind of food.
SANDRA:
Definitely,
and there’ll be loads of choice for the kids, too.
SANDRA:
You need to get there quite early though – at the weekend most of
the stalls stop serving lunch at 2.30.
MAN:
Good point.
It’s all going to need careful planning!
My cousin said she’d love to take the kids to a show at the theatre –
but tickets are so expensive!
SANDRA:
I know.
But you can get some good deals if you book online with bargaintickets.com for
the following day – on some seats there’s a 75% discount.
MAN:
Really?!
I must try and get some.
SANDRA:
Yeah.
There are lots of things you can do for free as well – no
need to spend a fortune.
MAN:
Like what?
SANDRA:
They’re coming next month, right?
Well, check and see if it’s the same weekend as the Roots Music Festival
in Blakewell Gardens.
MAN:
R double-O-T-S?
SANDRA:
Yeah.
Check it out online.
It’s always a family-friendly event and there’s no entry charge.
MAN:
That sounds perfect.
SANDRA:
And if you’re in Blakewell Gardens – climb Telegraph Hill – you’ll be able
to look right down on the port.
Everyone’s always really impressed because it’s so huge.
MAN:
Oh yeah – I’ve been meaning to do that for ages.
I’ve heard the view’s amazing.
SANDRA:
Yeah.
It’s really worth the effort.
MAN:
Well that’s given me loads of ideas.
Thanks so much …